Guide to the Mario Lombardo Scores MC.284
New York University Archives
Mario Lombardo Scores
1964-2010
New York University Archives
Lombardo, Mario
MC.284
7 linear feet in 5 record cartons, 2 small flat boxes, and 1 oversize flat box
Mario Lombardo (1930-2010) was an American composer based in New Jersey. Lombardo earned a Master's degree in English from Seton Hall University, where he also served as a professor. In the course of his professional career, Lombardo composed more than 200 songs, six musicals, and numerous works for chorus, orchestras, and specific instrumentations, many of which were performed by the orchestras both domestically and internationally. This collection consists of musical scores in various stages for Lombardo's compositions, including notebooks, drafts on staff paper, arrangements for specific parts, study scores, condensed scores, full scores, and sheet music. Works present in the collection include Variations in a Mod Mood, Drakestail, Serenade for Violin and Orchestra, Three Psalms of David, Blue Interlude, Near Nostalgia, and Late Autumn, in addition to other pieces for orchestra, piano, tenor voice, oboe, and violin.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of musical scores in various stages for the compositions of Mario Lombardo, including notebooks, drafts on staff paper, arrangements for specific parts, study scores, condensed scores, full scores, and sheet music. Works present in the collection include Variations in a Mod Mood, Drakestail, Serenade for Violin and Orchestra, Three Psalms of David, Blue Interlude, Near Nostalgia, and Late Autumn, in addition to other pieces for orchestra, piano, tenor voice, oboe, and violin.
Biographical Note
Mario Lombardo (1930-2010) was an American composer based in New Jersey. Lombardo earned a Master's degree in English from Seton Hall University, where he also served as a professor. He was a member of the American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), and was named the 1994 Musician of the Year by the New Jersey Conference of Musicians. In the course of his professional career, Lombardo composed more than 200 songs, six musicals, and numerous works for chorus, orchestras, and specific instrumentations, many of which were performed by the orchestras both domestically and internationally.
Source:
Cranford Chronicle. "Obituaries: Mario Lombardo, 80, Composed for Orchestras." http://www.nj.com/cranford/index.ssf/2012/01/obituaries_mario_lombardo_80_c.html (retrieved November 21, 2017).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Laura Szpir, Mario Lombardo's daughter, in September 2014; the accession number associated with this gift is 2017.052.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Original order is unknown.
Scores.; Composers -- United States -- 20th century; Orchestral music -- Scores
- Rhapsody for Oboe and Piano, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Scores [1 of 2], 1964-1965; 2005-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Scores [2 of 2], 1978; 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Mario Lombardo Songbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Late Autumn, Winter Frolic, and Other Scores, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Scores, 1972; 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Scores, 1969; 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Scores, 1992-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Escapade (for Orchestra) [Xerox], Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Escapade (for Orchestra), Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Near Nostalgia, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Winter Frolic, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Scores, 1964; 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Scores, 1991-1996; undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Scores, 1969; 1995-2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Scores, 1982-2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Scores, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Scores, 1992-1996; undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- On the Move (March for Orchestra), Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- On the Move - Orchestral Parts 1/2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- On the Move - Orchestral Parts 2/2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Scores, 1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Rhapsody for Oboe and Orchestra [1 of 2], Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Rhapsody for Oboe and Orchestra [2 of 2], Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Concerto for Oboe and Orchestra, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- A Citizen Song - Symphonic Arrangement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- If You Were Mine / The Hand of Love Divine, 1994; 2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Hand of Love Divine, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- On the Move / Music in Our Lives, 1992; 2010 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Blue Interlude, 1996; 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Scintillating Rhythm, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Scintillating Rhythm (for Strings, Woodwind, Percussion, and Optional Piano), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Winter Frolic / Music in Our Lives, 1982; 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Nothing Money Can't Buy, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Last Leaf, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Winter Frolic / A Midsummer Night's Waltz, 1975; 2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Starbright, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Early Spring / Late Autumn, Undated; 2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Blue Interlude (for Clarinet and Orchestra), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Serenade for Violin and Piano, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Spectrum for Orchestra, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- It's Worth Your Wile!, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Rock 'N Rhapsody, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Theme from Oboe Concert, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Blue Interlude for Clarinet and Piano, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Scores, 1974; 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Drakestail, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Early Spring, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Escapade, 1992; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Concerto for Oboe / Rhapsody for Oboe and Piano, 1991; 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Near Nostalgia, 2001; 2008 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Scores, 1998; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Late Autumn (for Violin, Strings, and Harp), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Scores, 1995; undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Variations in a Mod Mood, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- News Clippings, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Scherzo, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Rock 'N Rhapsody, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Display A Little Style, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Drakestail, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Modern Studies for the Piano (Book 1), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Modern Studies for the Piano (Book 2), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Modern Studies for the Piano (Book 3), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Display A Little Style (1st Draft), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Last Leaf, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- It's Worth Your Wile!, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Books for Piano, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Modern Studies for the Piano (Book 1), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Modern Studies for the Piano (Book 2), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Modern Studies for the Piano (Book 3), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Serenade for Violin and Piano, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Serenade for Violin + Orchestra, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Rhapsody for Oboe and Orchestra, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Jubilation Overture, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Display A Little Style (A Musical Comedy), Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Drakestail, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Elegy, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Gavotte, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Symphonic Ode, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- A Citizen Song, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Late Autumn (for Violin, Strings, and Harp), 2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Scores, 1991; 2006 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Winter Frolic, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- A Midsummer Night's Waltz (for Orchestra), 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Starbright, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- The Last Leaf, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Nothing Money Can't Buy, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Waltzing at the Waldorf, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Winter Frolic (for Strings, Flutes, and Percussion), Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ballad (for Oboe and Strings), 2008 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Waltz (for Oboe and Strings), 2008 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Scores, 2000-2008; undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Winter Frolic (for TTBB Chorus with Piano), Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Theme from Oboe Rhapsody, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Scores, 1992-2010 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- One Toy for Christmas, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Make A Joyful Noise for Chorus and Orchestra, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Sing Unto the Lord A New Song for Choir and Orchestra, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- The Lord is My Shepherd for Tenor Solo, Choir and Orchestra, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Theme from Oboe Concert, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- When I Fall in Love, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- We Worship and Adore You Lord, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- As I Recall Our Love, 1994; 1998 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- As I Recall Our Love - Aria for Tenor + Orchestra, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- All At Once (for Tenor + Orchestra), Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Until You Gave Your Love to Me, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- All At Once, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Piano Spectrum, Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Oboe + Piano Selections, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Notes, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Notes - Condensed Scores, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Notes - Psalms of David, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Notes - Choral Works, Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Notes - Songs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Song Book, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
- A Citizen Song (for Orchestra and Chorus), Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Scores, 1972; 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Scores, 1992-2007 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Scores, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Scores, 1991-2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Scores, 1995-2009 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Scores, 1995-2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- America -- The New Promised Land, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Scores, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- The Lord is My Shepherd (for Tenor, Chorus, and Orchestra), Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Make A Joyful Noise (for Chorus and Orchestra), Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Sing Unto the Lord A New Song (for Chorus and Orchestra) - Full Score, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Waltzing at the Waldorf (for Orchestra) - Full Score, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Spectrum (for Orchestra), Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Jubilation Overture (Condensed Score), 2008 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Orchestral Parts - Over the Rainbow (for Piano and Orchestra), Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Blue Interlude (for Clarinet and Orchestra), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Notes / Jubilation Overture (for Orchestra), Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Notes - Drakestail, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- On the Move, Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Volcanic Rock (Notes), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Until You Gave Your Love to Me, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Morning in Marseilles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
- 3 Psalms of David (for Chorus and Orchestra), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Now and Forever, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Multiple Pieces, 1996, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Multiple Pieces, 1995-2009 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Multiple Pieces, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Echoes of Love, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Spectrum (for Orchestra), Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Jubilation Overture (Full Score), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Over the Rainbow (for Piano + Orchestra), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Blue Interlude (for Clarinet + Orchestra), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Variations in a Mod Mood (Condensed Score), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Rock N' Rhapsody (Condensed Score), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Variations in a Mod Mood (Condensed Score), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A Midsummer Night's Waltz (for Orchestra) (Full Score), 2006 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Until You Gave Your Love to Me, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- All At Once, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- As I Recall Our Love, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Escapade (for Orchestra) (Condensed Score), Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Waltzing at the Waldorf (for Orchestra), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- On the Move (March for Orchestra), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Escapade (for Orchestra), Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Serenade for Violin and Orchestra (Full Score), 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Rock N' Rhapsody, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Volcanic Rock, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Revival (Full Score), Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- The Lord is My Shepherd, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Sing Unto the Lord A New Song, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- "Make A Joyful Noise" from Three Psalms of David, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)